Guide to the Philip Rose Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Philip Rose papers
1944-2007
YCAL MSS 438
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20
(20 boxes)
The Philip Rose Papers consist of correspondence, notes, contracts, photographs, drawings, printed material, and audiovisual recordings documenting the work of theatre producer Philip Rose. Rose's production files comprise the bulk of the collection, documenting the shows he produced in varying degrees of detail; the productions Purlie Victorious, Purlie, A Raisin in the Sun, Shenandoah, and Split Second are particularly well documented. Files for most productions include legal and financial documentation, scripts, scores, photographs, casting notes, lists of personnel, correspondence, marketing materials, playbills, and reviews. Audio and visual recordings chiefly document the original production of Shenandoah, but also include recordings of Purlie and You Shouldn't Have Told. The collection also includes drafts of Rose's 2004 memoir, You Can't Do That on Broadway!: A Raisin in the Sun and Other Theatrical Improbabilities, as well as other papers documenting Rose's career such as awards and memberships.
Rose, Philip, 1921-2011
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Locus Solus Rare Books on various funds, 2010. Please consult the appropriate curator for more information.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 13-16 (audiovisual material): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Philip Rose (1921-2011)
The Broadway producer Philip Rose was born in Manhattan on July 4, 1921, to Polish immigrants Max and Esther Rosenberg, the fourth of their five children. The family moved to Washington, D.C. in the 1930s, where Max Rosenberg opened a haberdashery, and the young Philip Rosenberg spent much of his time in the city's African American neighborhoods, initially through his work as a bill collector. He moved to New York in 1945 to pursue a career as a singer, changing his name to Philip Rose at that time. He met his wife, the actress Doris Belack, in 1946 while performing in a Gilbert and Sullivan production.
Rose enjoyed modest success as a music producer before becoming involved with the theatre in the 1950s, a change that came about when he read his friend Lorraine Hansberry's play, A Raisin in the Sun, a drama about an African American family in Chicago. Despite widespread skepticism about the commercial viability of the subject matter at the time, and with little experience in the theatre, Rose determined to bring the play to the stage. A Raisin in the Sun debuted in New Haven in 1958, directed by Lloyd Richards and with a cast including Sidney Poitier, Ruby Dee, and Diana Sands. After touring to Philadelphia and Chicago, it opened at the Ethel Barrymore Theatre in New York in March of 1959, breaking ground as the first play by a black woman and the first with a black director to open on Broadway. That year Hansberry won the New York Drama Critics' Circle Award for Best Play, and the production was nominated for four Tony Awards. The play's critical and commercial success had a lasting effect on American theatre and on cultural attitudes.
Rose went on to produce more than twenty other plays and musicals, the most successful among them being Purlie Victorious, a comedy about race relations in the South by Ossie Davis (1961); The Owl and The Pussycat (1964), which starred Alan Alda and Diana Sands in an interracial romance; Purlie, a musical based on the play (1970); and Shenandoah, a musical set during the Civil War (1975).
Rose died of a stroke on May 31, 2011 in Englewood, New Jersey.
Sources include The New York Times, 1 June 2011; The Washington Post, 8 June 2011; and Playbill.Com, 2 June 2011.
Scope and Contents
The Philip Rose Papers consist of correspondence, notes, contracts, photographs, drawings, printed material, and audiovisual recordings documenting the work of theatre producer Philip Rose. Rose's production files comprise the bulk of the collection, documenting the shows he produced in varying degrees of detail; the productions Purlie Victorious, Purlie, A Raisin in the Sun, Shenandoah, and Split Second are particularly well documented. Files for most productions include legal and financial documentation, scripts, scores, photographs, casting notes, lists of personnel, correspondence, marketing materials, playbills, and reviews. Audio and visual recordings chiefly document the original production of Shenandoah, but also include recordings of Purlie and You Shouldn't Have Told. The collection also includes drafts of Rose's 2004 memoir, You Can't Do That on Broadway!: A Raisin in the Sun and Other Theatrical Improbabilities, as well as other papers documenting Rose's career such as awards and memberships.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. General Correspondence, 1961-1991. II. Production Files, 1956-2007. III. Writings, 1995-2004. IV. Other Papers, 1959-2006. V. Audiovisual Material, circa 1970-1998.
African Americans -- Drama; American drama -- 20th Century; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States -- Archives; Theater -- Production and direction -- New York (State) -- New York; Theater -- United States; Musicals -- Scores; Broadway (New York, N.Y.) -- History; United States -- Race relations -- Drama; Audiovisual materials; Photographs; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States; Davis, Ossie ( Purlie victorious); Dee, Ruby, 1922-2014; Hansberry, Lorraine, 1930-1965 ( Lorraine Hansberry's A raisin in the sun); Poitier, Sidney, 1927-; Richards, Lloyd, 1919-2006; Rose, Philip, 1921-2011
- General Correspondence, 1961-1991; Series I; 2
  Arrangement
  Material is arranged in chronological order.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. contains general correspondence that does not concern a specific or single production.
  Related Archival Materials note
  Correspondence concerning specific productions can be found in Series II.
  - Opening-night telegrams and notes, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Good wishes addressed to Philip Rose and Doris Belack from correspondents including Ossie Davis and Ruby Dee, Lloyd Richards, Neil Simon, and each spouse to the other for Purlie Victorious and P.S. 193, a production in which Belack starred in 1962 at The Writer's Stage.
  - General correspondence, 1969-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes photocopy of letter to Rose from Ed Bullins written in 1969.
- Production Files, 1957-2007; Series II; 8.25; (9 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by title. Material concerning each production is arranged in rough chronological order. Some unsorted material is filed at the end of the series.
  The series contains Philip Rose's production files for theatre productions. While files for some shows contain only a few items, files for more richly documented productions include legal and financial documentation, scripts, scores, set design drawings, photographs, casting notes, lists of personnel, correspondence, printed material including playbills and reviews, and documentation concerning film adaptations.
  - Amen Corner, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contains documents and photographs.
  - By the Sword
    - Business documents, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Casting, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Movie Group contract, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Certificate of incorporation, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Expenses, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - By the Sword seals, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chemical Bank, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Movie Group Inc., correspondence and documentation, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tax information, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Budgets, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - Personnel crew, etc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Settlement agreements - Movie Group, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Settlement correspondence - Movie Group, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Publicity material - Movie Group, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Tax forms, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Old correspondence, reviews, etc., 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Tax return, 1991, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - New York opening, 1993 October (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Captain America, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Cemetery Club, 1990-1997
    - Bank and legal correspondence, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Binder, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Cancelled checks, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Casting notebook, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Partnership correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Documents, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Tax documentation, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Legal documents, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Playbills, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Checkmates, 1988-1989
    - Binder - documents and photographs, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - King, Woody - agreements, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Checkmates - agreement, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Comin' Uptown, 1979-1990
    - Binder - documents and photographs, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Press clippings, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - "Uptown Christmas Eve", script, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Demchuck, Bob - "Christmas is Comin' Uptown" agreement, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Sing a Christmas Song, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Does a Tiger Wear a Necktie? - Don Petersen script, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Don't Let This Dream Go - Ford's Theatre, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Late Night Comic, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
  - Look Homeward, Angel - Glen Cove, N.Y. reviews, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - My Old Friends, 1978-1985
    - Playbills and reviews, 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Binder - documents and photographs, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Nobody Loves an Albatross - playbills, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - The Owl and the Pussycat - production photographs and playbill, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Purlie Victorious / Purlie, 1961-2007
    - Guest register for cast party, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Opening night reviews, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Prompt book, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Reviews, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Script, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Reviews, 1961-1971 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Reviews and publicity material, playbill, 1962-1972 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      Contains Ebony magazine, Vol. XVII No. 5, March 1962.
    - Stern, Wincor & Burns correspondence, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Ampex Corp. statements, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Daily reviews, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Investors list, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Publicity materials, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Sheet music, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 67-68)
    - Stern, Wincor & Burns correspondence, 1970 October 6 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Udell, Peter and Gary Geld correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - The Victorious Company, limited partnership agreement, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Photographs, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 72-73)
    - Printing block, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Scripts, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 75-76)
    - Publicity material and photographs, playbills, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Financial documents and correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Financial documents and correspondence (continued), 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Purlie scrapbook, 1970-1972 (Box 17 Oversize, Folder 80)
    - Reviews, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 81-83)
    - Reviews, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Samuel French, Inc., correspondence, 1970-1988 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Reviews, scores and legal documents, 1970-1996 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Certified audit - year ending January 2, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Certified audit, The Victorious Company, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 88-89)
    - Hospital Audiences, Inc., correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Payroll documents, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Pinto, Winokur & Pagano, correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 92-93)
    - Investors list, 1971-1981 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Certified audit as of 1972 [empty folder], circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Envelope [empty], circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 96)
      Addressed to Cincinnati, Ohio production of Purlie.
    - Revenue sheets, The Victorious Company., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Review, 1972 March 15 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - The Victorious Company, audit, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Cancelled checks, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - I.R.S. tax settlement, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Investor correspondence, 1973-1981 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Samuel French, Inc. correspondence and royalty list, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - I.R.S Victorious Company settlement, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Legal documents and correspondence, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Thiels, Robert - contract with CBS regarding cable show, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Legal correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Legal documents and correspondence - Purlie cable show, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Royalty statements - Purlie cable show, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Author's royalties, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Legal documents and correspondence, 1999, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Broadway revival, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - A Raisin in the Sun, 1957-2002
    - A Raisin in the Sun - script by Lorraine Hansberry, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 113-114)
    - Hughes, Langston - correspondence regarding play, photocopy, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Correspondence and photographs, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 116-117)
      Includes correspondence from Lorraine Hansberry Nemiroff, Langston Hughes, Lloyd Richards, and Rose. Removed from binder.
    - Guest book, circa 1959 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Israeli rights to A Raisin in the Sun, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Mervyn Williams prompt copy, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Mounted photographs and poster, circa 1959 (Box 17 Oversize, Folder 121)
    - Opening night - telegrams, 1959 March 11 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Out-of-town reviews, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Reviews and clippings, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Villiage Voice, regarding Lorraine Hansberry, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Photographs, 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Public relations, photocopies, 1959, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Script - Columbia Pictures, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Reviews, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Public relations / marketing - Capital Repertory Theatre, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Published script, photocopy (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Playbills, 1959-2004 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Shenandoah, 1974-1997
    - Reviews, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 133-134)
    - Scores, 1974 (Box 18 Oversize, Folder 135-136)
    - Scores, 1974 (Box 19 Oversize, Folder 137-138)
    - Scores, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Published script and review, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - Tony Awards, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Script and reviews, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Headshots, correspondence and reviews., 1974-1982 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Reviews, 1974-1989 (Box 6, Folder 144)
      Contains reviews of other plays.
    - Reviews, 1974-1989 (Box 6, Folder 145-146)
    - Investors list, 1974-1990 (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Production photographs, circa 1975 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Stage concept drawings, circa 1975 (Box 20 Oversize, Folder 150)
    - Playbills and cast recording liner notes, 1974-2006 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Investors correspondence and statements, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Pinto, Winokur & Pagano, correspondence, 1976 Dec 9 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Gingerbread Productions, Inc. - "Bus and Truck", 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Shenandoah Investor Royalties, 1976-1996 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Binder: documents and photographs, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 156)
      Contains some material regarding the musical Angel.
    - Paramus Playhouse on the Mall - agreement, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Tax documents, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Reviews and correspondence, 1979-1989 (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - RCA royalty statements, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Investors - 'Return to Sender', 1979-1990 (Box 6, Folder 161-163)
    - Shenandoah Company expenses, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Shenandoah cable show, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Financial correspondence and documents, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Chemical Bank - Shenandoah Company, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Chemical Bank - Shenandoah Company, 1983-1990s (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Shenandoah tax documents, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 169-171)
    - Financial documents - Shenandoah Company, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 172-173)
    - Chemical Bank - Shenandoah Company, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Financial documents - Shenandoah Company, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 175-176)
    - Royalty and financial material, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Shenandoah tax returns, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Financial documents - Shenandoah Company, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Shenandoah tax returns, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Financial documents - Shenandoah Company, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Shenandoah tax returns, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Shenandoah tax documents, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Shenandoah Company - tax returns, 1993-1984 (Box 7, Folder 185-186)
    - Accountant's report on Financial documents - Shenandoah Company, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - Financial documents - Financial documents - Shenandoah Company Company, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Investor correspondence, 1989-1997 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Split Second, 1983-1994
    - Legal and financial documents, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - Affidavits, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Balance book, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Certificate of Notice of Formation, 1984 June 1 (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - Chemical Bank - duplicates, checks and affidavits, circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Correspondence and documents, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 195-196)
    - Financial documents and correspondence, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 197-198)
    - Goldberg, Bobby - correspondence, 1984 August 23 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Limited Partnership Agreement "Split Second", 1984 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Motown agreement, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Photographs, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - Photographs and reviews, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Playbills, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Questionable bills, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Reviews, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Rose, Philip - agreements, circa 1984 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Unpaid bills, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Chemical Bank - Split Second Company, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 209-210)
    - Motown - correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - Paid bills, to be audited, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Reinis-Perrotti Productions - San Francisco Company, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Alcazar Theatre - San Francisco, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Binder: documents and photographs, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 215)
      Contains contact information for the play The Trip Back Down.
    - General reviews - stock & amateur, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Mayfair Theatre - Los Angeles, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Future companies, 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - Financial documents, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 219)
    - Legal documents and correspondence, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 220)
    - Victory Gardens Theatre, circa 1985 (Box 9, Folder 221)
    - Woolridge, Hugh - agreement, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 222)
    - Chemical Bank, 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 223)
    - Mayfair Theatre - Los Angeles, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - Samuel French, Inc. - agreement, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - Chemical Bank - Split Second Company, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Samuel French, Inc. - statements, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - Correspondence and financial documents, 1988-1994 (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - The Trip Back Down, 1975-1977
    - Rose, Philip - Columbia agreement, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Columbia Pictures agreement, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 230)
  - Truly Blessed, 1990
    - Binder: documents, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Reviews, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 232)
  - Additional production-related material, 1950s-2005
    - Photographs, 1950s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 233)
      Contains an autographed photograph of Sidney Poitier.
    - Reviews and clippings, 1950s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 234-235)
    - Clippings and correspondence, photocopies, 1950s-2005 (Box 9, Folder 236)
      Contains a copy of Philip Rose's memorial for Ossie Davis.
    - Show photographs, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - Reviews, 1960s-2000 (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Clippings, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - Sheet music, 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 240)
      Contains music for the musicals Amen Corner and Shenandoah.
    - Clippings and documents regarding various productions, 1974-2001 (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Chorus replacements, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 242)
    - Reviews and documents, 1979-2002 (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - "(It's Gonna Be A) Lonely Christmas", score (Box 9, Folder 244)
- Writings, 1995-2004; Series III; 2; (2 boxes)
  This series contains drafts, proofs, and background material for Philip Rose's memoir, You Can't Do That on Broadway!: A Raisin in the Sun and Other Theatrical Inprobabilities, published in 2004.
  - Various manuscript and typescript drafts, 1995-2002 (Box 10, Folder 245-249)
  - "Broadway and Beyond", early drafts, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 250-252)
  - "How Did It Happen?", early draft, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - Chapter 19 drafts, 2000-2004 (Box 11, Folder 254-255)
  - Later manuscript drafts, 2000-2004 (Box 11, Folder 256-258)
  - "You Can't Do That on Broadway", proofs, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 259-261)
  - Annotated folder, undated (Box 11, Folder 262)
  - Photocopies for memoir, undated (Box 11, Folder 263)
    Contains photocopies of clippings and letters.
- Other Papers, 1969-2006; Series IV; 0.5; (1 box)
  Organized into two subseries: Awards and Other Material. Material is arranged in rough chronological order within each.
  Series IV contains awards, personal papers, printed ephemera and other papers documenting Rose's career as a producer and his general interests. Photographs include formal portraits of Rose from the 1950s-1970s as well as candid images of him with others, including Sidney Poitier.
  - Awards
    - Antoinette Perry award nomination certificates, 1969-1975 (Box 12, Folder 264)
    - American Film Institute Life Achievement Award booklet - Sidney Poitier, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 265)
    - Philip Rose nomination - Rosetta LeNoire Award, photocopies, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 266-267)
    - Rosetta LeNoire Award, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 268-269)
    - The Black Academy of Arts and Letters - 30th Anniversary, booklets, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 270)
  - Other Material
    - Photographs of Philip Rose and friends, 1970s-2005 (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - "A Study of the Adaptation of the Play Purlie Victorious into the Musical Purlie", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 272)
      Contains a 1972 thesis by Robert Russell Hunter, A.A., B.A.
    - American Society of Composers membership extension, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 273)
    - Timeline of Martin Luther King, Jr., printout., 1999 (Box 12, Folder 274)
    - 157 W. 57th Street lease, circa 1989 (Box 12, Folder 275)
    - Various magazines and publications, 1989-2006 (Box 12, Folder 276)
    - American Theatre, Vol. XVIII, No. 8, 2001 October (Box 12, Folder 277)
    - Ebony magazine, Vol. LVII, No. 5, 2002 March (Box 12, Folder 278)